Register of the Frances E. Willis Papers, 1906-1983.
Hoover Institution Archives
Frances E. Willis Papers,
1906-1983
84031
Willis, Frances E.
39 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 3 album boxes, 35 envelopes, memorabilia (18.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, speeches, memoranda, reports, bulletins, printed matter, and photographs, relating to post-World War II American foreign policy, especially in Switzerland, Norway, and Ceylon.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1984.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
United States. Dept. of State.; Norway.; Norway--Foreign relations--United States.; Sri Lanka.; Sri Lanka--Foreign relations--United States.; Switzerland.; Switzerland--Foreign relations--United States.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Foreign relations--Norway.; United States--Foreign relations--Sri Lanka.; United States--Foreign relations--Switzerland.; Diplomats--United States.
Biographical Note
1899, May 20 Born, Metropolis, Illinois
1916-1917 University of Redlands
1917-1920 B.A., History, Stanford University
1920-1921 Graduate work, Universite Libre de Bruxelles
1923 Ph.D., Political Science, Stanford University
1923-1924 Instructor, History, Goucher College, Baltimore, Maryland
1924-1927 Assistant Professor, Political Science, Vassar College, Poughkeepsie, New York
1927 Foreign Service Exam Vice-Consul, Valparaiso, Chile
1931, January Vice-Consul, Santiago, Chile
1931, December Third Secretary, Stockholm, Sweden
1934-1940 Third Secretary, Brussels, Belgium Second Secretary, Luxembourg
1940-1944 Second Secretary, Madrid, Spain First Secretary, Madrid, Spain Consul, Madrid, Spain
1944-1947 Assistant to the Undersecretary of State, Washington, D.C.
1947-1951 First Secretary and Consul, London, England
1951-1953 Counselor of Legation, Helsinki, Finland
1953-1957 Ambassador to Switzerland
1955 Appointed Career Minister
1957-1961 Ambassador to Norway
1962 Appointed Career Ambassador
1961-1964 Ambassador to Sri Lanka
1964, November 5 Retirement
1983, July 20 Died, Redlands, California
Series Description
- Early Life, 1906-1927. (Box No. 1-3.)
  Grammar school, high school and university papers, scrapbooks, doctoral thesis, and printed matter, arranged chronologically.
- Biographical File, 1946-1965. (Box No. 3.)
  Articles and biographical data, arranged chronologically.
- Family Correspondence, 1920-1966. (Box No. 3-14.)
  Letters and copies of letters from Frances E. Willis to her family, and other family correspondence, arranged chronologically.
- Foreign Service, 1927-1953. (Box No. 14-17.)
  Correspondence, clippings, memoranda, speeches, career records, arranged chronologically.
- Ambassador to Switzerland, 1953-1957. (Box No. 17-20.)
  Correspondence, speeches, memoranda, notes, reports, printed matter, arranged by form.
- Ambassador to Norway, 1957-1961. (Box No. 21-23.)
  Correspondence, speeches, visits, memoranda, printed matter, arranged by form.
- Ambassador to Sri Lanka, 1961-1964. (Box No. 24-31.)
- Post Retirement, 1964-1983. (Box No. 32-38.)
  Correspondence, speeches, visits, printed matter, arranged by form.
- Memorabilia, 1920-1977. (Box No. 39.)
  Identity cards, passports, guest book, stamp books, diplomas, etc.
- Photographs, ca. 1916-1977. (Albums A-C, Envelopes D-AL.)
  Arranged chronologically.
Container List
- EARLY LIFE, 1899-1928
  - Grammar school papers (Box 1.)
    - 1906 (Folder 1)
    - 1910 (Folder 2)
    - 1910-1911 (Folder 3)
  - High school (Kemper Hall), 1911-1915
    - Scrapbook (Folder 4)
    - Report card, medals, and honor roll (Folder 5)
  - Undergraduate university education (Box 2.)
    - Class notes, history (Folder 1)
    - Papers
      - "Sino-Japanese Relations, 1914-1915" (Folder 2)
      - "Woodrow Wilson's Theory of Party Government," December 7, 1921 (Folder 3)
    - Stanford University Commencement (Folder 4)
  - Post-graduate education
    - University of Brussels, 1921-1922 (Folder 5)
    - Doctoral thesis, "The Belgian Parliamentary System," June 1923 (Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous printed matter, 1920-1924 (Folder 7)
  - Teaching career. The Vassar Miscellany News, May 15, 1926 (article mentioning F. E. Willis) (Box 3., Folder 1)
  - Foreign Service School
    - "The Road to Success, or the Career of a Diplomat," by M. C. Perts, 1924. Book of drawings (Folder 2)
    - American Academy of Political and Social Sciences, 31st Annual Meeting, April 22-23, 1927. Program (Folder 3)
    - "How Much Did You Pay for Your Job?, an Obsolete Mystery Play in Modern Dress, a Prologue, and an Act," presented by The Foreign Service School, Department of State, Washington D. C. (Folder 4)
    - "The Elements of Sea Power and Its Meaning to the United States," by William Howard Gardiner. Lecture given to the Foreign Service School, February 13, 1928 (Folder 4a)
    - "Naval Power in War and as a Peaceful Support of Policy," by William Howard Gardiner. Lecture given to the Foreign Service School, February 13, 1928 (Folder 4b)
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1946-1965.
  - Articles and biographical data (Box 3., Folder 5)
  - Undated (Folder 6)
  - 1920
    - May (Folder 7)
    - August (Folder 8)
    - September (Folder 9)
    - October (Folder 10)
    - November (Folder 11)
    - December (Folder 12)
  - 1921
    - January (Folder 13)
    - February (Folder 14)
    - March (Folder 15)
    - April (Folder 16)
    - May (Box 4., Folder 1)
    - June (Folder 2)
    - July (Folder 3)
  - 1932
    - January (Folder 4)
    - February (Folder 5)
    - March (Folder 6)
    - April (Folder 7)
    - May (Folder 8)
    - June (Folder 9)
    - July (Folder 10)
    - August (Folder 11)
    - September (Folder 12)
    - October (Folder 13)
    - November (Folder 14)
    - December (Folder 15)
  - 1933
    - January (Folder 16)
    - February (Folder 17)
    - March (Folder 18)
    - April (Folder 19)
    - May (Folder 20)
    - June (Folder 21)
    - July (Folder 22)
    - August (Folder 23)
    - September (Folder 24)
    - October (Folder 25)
  - 1934 (Box 5.)
    - July (Folder 1)
    - August (Folder 2)
    - September (Folder 3)
    - October (Folder 4)
    - November (Folder 5)
    - December (Folder 6)
  - 1935
    - January (Folder 7)
    - February (Folder 8)
    - March (Folder 9)
    - April (Folder 10)
    - May (Folder 11)
    - June (Folder 12)
    - July (Folder 13)
    - August (Folder 14)
    - September (Folder 15)
    - October (Folder 16)
    - November (Folder 17)
    - December (Folder 18)
  - 1936 (Box 6.)
    - January (Folder 1)
    - February (Folder 2)
    - March (Folder 3)
    - April (Folder 4)
    - May (Folder 5)
  - 1937
    - January (Folder 6)
    - February (Folder 7)
    - March (Folder 8)
    - April (Folder 9)
    - May (Folder 10)
    - June (Folder 11)
    - July (Folder 12)
    - August (Folder 13)
    - September (Folder 14)
    - October (Folder 15)
    - November (Folder 16)
    - December (Folder 17)
  - 1938
    - January (Folder 18)
    - February (Folder 19)
    - March (Folder 20)
    - April (Folder 21)
    - May (Folder 22)
    - June (Folder 23)
    - July (Folder 24)
    - August (Folder 25)
    - September (Folder 26)
    - October (Folder 27)
    - November (Folder 28)
    - December (Folder 29)
  - 1939 (Box 7.)
    - January (Folder 1)
    - February (Folder 2)
    - March (Folder 3)
    - April (Folder 4)
    - May (Folder 5)
    - June (Folder 6)
    - July (Folder 7)
    - August (Folder 8)
    - September (Folder 9)
    - October (Folder 10)
    - November (Folder 11)
    - December (Folder 12)
  - 1940
    - January (Folder 13)
    - February (Folder 14)
    - March (Folder 15)
    - April (Folder 16)
    - May (Folder 17)
    - June (Folder 18)
    - July (Folder 19)
    - August (Folder 20)
    - September (Folder 21)
    - October (Folder 22)
    - November (Folder 23)
    - December (Folder 24)
  - 1941
    - January (Folder 25)
    - February (Folder 26)
    - March (Folder 27)
    - May (Folder 28)
    - June (Folder 29)
    - July (Folder 30)
    - August (Folder 31)
    - September (Folder 32)
    - October (Folder 33)
    - November (Folder 34)
    - December (Folder 35)
  - 1942 (Box 8.)
    - January (Folder 1)
    - February (Folder 2)
    - March (Folder 3)
    - April (Folder 4)
    - May (Folder 5)
    - June (Folder 6)
    - July (Folder 7)
    - August (Folder 8)
    - September (Folder 9)
    - October (Folder 10)
    - November (Folder 11)
    - December (Folder 12)
  - 1943
    - January (Folder 13)
    - February (Folder 14)
    - March (Folder 15)
    - April (Folder 16)
    - May (Folder 17)
    - June (Folder 18)
    - July (Folder 19)
    - August (Folder 20)
    - September (Folder 21)
    - October (Folder 22)
    - November (Folder 23)
    - December (Folder 24)
  - 1944
    - January (Folder 25)
    - February (Folder 26)
    - March (Folder 27)
    - April (Folder 28)
    - May (Folder 29)
    - June (Folder 30)
    - July (Folder 31)
    - August (Folder 32)
  - 1945
    - June (Folder 33)
    - July (Folder 34)
    - August (Folder 35)
    - September (Folder 36)
    - October (Folder 37)
    - November (Folder 38)
    - December (Folder 39)
  - 1946 (Box 9.)
    - April (Folder 1)
    - May (Folder 2)
    - June (Folder 3)
    - August (Folder 4)
    - September (Folder 5)
    - October (Folder 6)
    - November (Folder 7)
    - December (Folder 8)
  - 1947
    - January (Folder 9)
    - February (Folder 10)
    - March (Folder 11)
    - April (Folder 12)
    - May (Folder 13)
    - June (Folder 14)
    - July (Folder 15)
    - August (Folder 16)
    - September (Folder 17)
    - October (Folder 18)
    - November (Folder 19)
    - December (Folder 20)
  - 1948
    - January (Folder 21)
    - February (Folder 22)
    - March (Folder 23)
    - April (Box 10.1)
    - May (Folder 2)
    - June (Folder 3)
    - July (Folder 4)
    - August (Folder 5)
    - September (Folder 6)
    - October (Folder 7)
    - November (Folder 8)
    - December (Folder 9)
  - 1949
    - January (Folder 10)
    - February (Folder 11)
    - March (Folder 12)
    - April (Folder 13)
    - May (Folder 14)
    - June (Folder 15)
    - July (Folder 16)
    - August (Folder 17)
    - September (Folder 18)
    - October (Folder 19)
    - November (Folder 20)
  - 1950
    - January (Folder 21)
    - February (Folder 22)
    - March (Folder 23)
    - April (Box 11.1)
    - May (Folder 2)
    - June (Folder 3)
    - July (Folder 4)
    - August (Folder 5)
    - September (Folder 6)
    - October (Folder 7)
    - November (Folder 8)
    - December (Folder 9)
  - 1951
    - January (Folder 10)
    - February (Folder 11)
    - March (Folder 12)
    - April (Folder 13)
    - May (Folder 14)
    - June (Folder 15)
    - July (Folder 16)
    - August (Folder 17)
    - September (Folder 18)
    - October (Folder 19)
    - November (Folder 20)
    - December (Folder 21)
  - 1952 (Box 12.)
    - January (Folder 1)
    - February (Folder 2)
    - March (Folder 3)
    - April (Folder 4)
    - May (Folder 5)
    - June (Folder 6)
    - July (Folder 7)
    - August (Folder 8)
    - September (Folder 9)
    - October (Folder 10)
    - November (Folder 11)
    - December (Folder 12)
  - 1953
    - January (Folder 13)
    - February (Folder 14)
    - March (Folder 15)
    - April (Folder 16)
    - May (Folder 17)
    - June (Folder 18)
    - July (Folder 19)
    - August (Folder 20)
    - September (Folder 21)
    - October (Folder 22)
    - November (Folder 23)
    - December (Folder 24)
  - 1954 (Box 13.)
    - January (Folder 1)
    - February (Folder 2)
    - March (Folder 3)
    - April (Folder 4)
    - May (Folder 5)
    - June (Folder 6)
    - July (Folder 7)
    - August (Folder 8)
    - September (Folder 9)
    - October (Folder 10)
    - November (Folder 11)
  - 1958
    - April (Folder 12)
    - June (Folder 13)
    - July (Folder 14)
    - August (Folder 15)
    - September (Folder 16)
    - October (Folder 17)
    - November (Folder 18)
    - December (Folder 19)
  - 1959
    - January (Folder 20)
    - February (Folder 21)
    - March (Folder 22)
    - April (Folder 23)
    - May (Folder 24)
    - June (Folder 25)
    - July (Folder 26)
    - August (Folder 27)
    - September (Folder 28)
    - October (Folder 29)
    - December (Folder 30)
  - 1960
    - January (Folder 31)
    - February (Folder 32)
    - March (Folder 33)
    - April (Folder 34)
    - May (Folder 35)
    - June (Folder 36)
    - July (Folder 37)
    - August (Folder 38)
    - September (Folder 39)
    - October (Folder 40)
    - November (Folder 41)
    - December (Folder 42)
  - 1961
    - January (Folder 43)
    - February (Folder 44)
    - March (Folder 45)
    - April (Folder 46)
    - May (Folder 47)
    - June (Folder 48)
    - July (Folder 49)
    - August (Folder 50)
    - September (Folder 51)
    - October (Folder 52)
    - November (Folder 53)
    - December (Folder 54)
  - 1962 (Box 14.)
    - January (Folder 1)
    - February (Folder 2)
    - March (Folder 3)
    - April (Folder 4)
    - May (Folder 5)
    - June (Folder 6)
    - July (Folder 7)
    - August (Folder 8)
    - September (Folder 9)
    - October (Folder 10)
    - November (Folder 11)
    - December (Folder 12)
  - 1963
    - January (Folder 13)
    - February (Folder 14)
    - March (Folder 15)
    - May (Folder 16)
    - June (Folder 17)
    - July (Folder 18)
    - August (Folder 19)
    - September (Folder 20)
    - October (Folder 21)
    - November (Folder 22)
    - December (Folder 23)
  - 1964
    - January (Folder 24)
    - February (Folder 25)
    - March (Folder 26)
    - April (Folder 27)
    - May (Folder 28)
    - June (Folder 29)
    - July (Folder 30)
  - 1966. November (Folder 31)
- FOREIGN SERVICE, 1927-1953.
  - Career records, including correspondence, memoranda, expense reports, clippings, printed matter, memorabilia, miscellany. (Box 14.)
  - Miscellaneous printer matter (Folder 31a)
  - 1927 (Folder 32)
  - 1928 (Folder 33)
  - 1929 (Folder 34)
  - 1930 (Folder 35)
  - 1931 (Folder 36)
  - 1932 (Box 15., Folder 1-3)
  - 1933 (Folder 4-5)
  - 1934 (Folder 6)
  - 1935 (Folder 7)
  - 1936 (Folder 8)
  - 1937 (Folder 9)
  - 1938. Executive orders from F. D. Roosevelt (Folder 10)
    - September 3
    - December 27
  - 1939. Executive orders from F. D. Roosevelt (Folder 11)
    - June 22
    - July 8
    - July 17
    - November 30
    - December 4
  - 1940. Includes The Case for the King of the Belgians, by John Cudahy (1940) (Folder 12)
  - 1941 (Box 16., Folder 1)
  - 1942 (Folder 2)
  - 1943 (Folder 3)
  - 1944 (Folder 4)
  - 1945 (Folder 5)
  - 1946 (Folder 6)
  - 1947 (Folder 7)
  - 1948 (Folder 8)
  - 1949 (Folder 9)
  - 1950 (Box 17., Folder 1)
  - 1951 (Folder 2)
  - 1952 (Folder 3)
  - 1953 (Folder 4)
- AMBASSADOR TO SWITZERLAND, 1953-1957
  - Correspondence, 1953-1957 (Box 17.)
    - Undated (Folder 5)
    - 1953 (Folder 6)
    - 1954 (Folder 7)
    - 1955 (Folder 8)
    - 1956 (Folder 9)
    - 1957 (Folder 10)
  - Chronological file of speeches and visits. Holograph notes, typewritten outline and text, correspondence. (Box 18.)
    - Undated drafts and holograph notes (Folder 1)
    - "Freedom Has Responsibilities," 1953 (Folder 2)
    - Appointment as Ambassador, statement for press and television, August 10, 1953
    - Voice of America broadcast, August 14, 1953
    - Presentation of credentials, October 9, 1953
    - Statement for press conference, October 9, 1953
    - "The Foreign Policy of the United States," Swiss Friends of the United States of America, Zurich, November 7, 1953
    - Visit to Canton of Vaud, January 20, 1954 (Folder 3)
    - University of Lausanne, January 20, 1954
    - Swiss-American Society for Cultural Relations, January 20, 1954
    - "What Has Been Accomplished 1945-1954," American Club of Geneva, January 21, 1954
    - Reception, Government of the Canton of Basel, May 12, 1954
    - American Books Exhibition, Zurich, June 21, 1954
    - Museum of Fine Arts, Lucerne, July 17, 1954
    - CBS Coast to Coast Broadcast, December 17, 1954
    - University of Redlands, Redlands, California, December 17, 1954
    - Berne Women's Club, January 7, 1955 (Folder 4)
    - Farewell to Egyptian Minister, January 14, 1955
    - Colombia Society, University of Fribourg, January 20, 1955
    - Ed Murrow Program, February 3, 1955
    - "Some Aspects of Life in the United States," International Forum, Geneva, March 9, 1955
    - Musical Salute between Basel, Switzerland, and Denver, Colorado, recording made at Radio Bern, May 17, 1955 (Folder 5)
    - "Some Aspects of Life in the United States of America," Swiss Institute of International Studies, Zurich, May 23, 1955
    - "Americans Abroad," Federation of American Women's Clubs Overseas, Zurich, May 24, 1955
    - "The Individual and International Cooperation," General Federation of Women's Clubs, Geneva, June 1, 1955 (Folder 6)
    - Confrerie des Vignerons de Vevey, August 1, 1955 (Folder 7)
    - Ceremony Transferring the United States Reactor to Switzerland, August 20, 1955
    - International Federation of Business and Professional Women, August 22, 1955
    - United States Information Agency, tape recording, October 10, 1955 (Folder 8)
    - Opening of the Comedie Francaise, New York, October 25, 1955
    - Sixty-ninth Anniversary of the Statue of Liberty, Bedloe's Island, October 28, 1955
    - Virginia Women's Forum, Richmond, Virginia, November 3, 1955 (Folder 9)
    - Newspaper Women's Club, Inc., New York, ca. November 19, 1955
    - American Women's Association, Annual Achievement Award, New York, November 19, 1955
    - Georgetown Junior Year Luncheon, Fribourg, Switzerland, January 25, 1956 (Folder 10)
    - Remarks on the Role of the Ambassador, Soleure, Switzerland, March 13, 1956
    - ABC Radio Broadcast, July 10, 1956
    - Presentation of an Atomic Energy Library to the Swiss Government, Zurich, August 15, 1956
    - Remarks at reception, Fribourg, Switzerland, September 24, 1956
    - Fragment of speech, Geneva, November 2, 1956
    - Bern Art Museum, January 26, 1957 (Folder 11)
    - Kiwanis Club, Redlands, California, March 27, 1957
    - Reply to speech by President Streuli, April 26, 1957
  - Subject File, 1953-1957. Correspondence, memoranda, career records, speeches, honorary degree, etc. (Box 19.)
    - Appointment to Switzerland (Folder 1)
    - Archives Diplomatiques et Consulaires, July/August, 1955 (Folder 2)
    - Attorney General's List of Subversive Organizations (Folder 3)
    - Brown, Winthrop G. Advance text of remarks to be delivered at a luncheon of the Swiss Friends of the U.S.A., January 27, 1955 (Folder 4)
    - Career records. Appraisal of language proficiency, bond, leave reports, residency and dependency reports, salary, etc. (Folder 5)
    - Customs information (Folder 6)
    - Department of State instructions (Folder 7)
    - Departure from Switzerland. Remarks addressed to F. E. Willis, April 17, 1957 (Folder 8)
    - Dillon, Ambassador (Thomas P. ?). Speech at American Club, Geneva, May 17, 1956 (Folder 9)
    - Dulles, John Foster. Remarks to the U.S. House of Representatives Foreign Affairs Committee, January 7, ca. 1956; Remarks to Girls Nation, July 12, 1956 (Folder 10)
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D. Thanksgiving Proclamations, n.d.; Address to Congress, January 6, 1957; Message to the President of the Swiss Confederation, n.d. (Folder 11)
    - Entertainment. Guest lists, accounts, calling cards (Folder 12)
    - Expenses of the Embassy
      - Miscellaneous (Folder 13)
      - 1953-1954 (Folder 14)
      - 1955 (Folder 15)
      - 1956 (Folder 16)
      - 1957 (Folder 17)
    - Foreign Policy Briefs (Folder 18)
    - Foreign Service Circular (Folder 19)
    - Foreign Service. Security Information Bulletin (Folder 20)
    - Honorary Degree from University of Redlands, December 16, 1954; Western College for Women, Oxford, Ohio, October 15, 1955 (Folder 21)
    - Household employees and inventory (Folder 22)
    - Lodge, Ambassador Henry Cabot, Jr. Statement on disarmament, January 14, 1957 (Folder 23)
    - Members of the Diplomatic Corps in Switzerland, December 21, 1954 (Folder 24)
    - Memoranda (Folder 25)
    - Menus, invitations, programs, etc. (Box 20.1)
    - Miscellany (Folder 2)
    - Newsbriefs (Folder 3)
    - Press releases (Folder 4)
    - Printed material (Folder 5)
    - Schedules, phone calls, appointments (Folder 6)
    - Travel vouchers and itineraries (Folder 7)
    - U.S. employees in Switzerland (Folder 8)
    - Women (Folder 9)
  - Clippings, 1953-1957
    - Undated (Folder 10)
    - 1953 (Folder 11)
    - 1954 (Folder 12)
    - 1955 (Folder 13)
    - 1956 (Folder 14)
    - 1957 (Folder 15)
- AMBASSADOR TO NORWAY, 1957-1961
  - Correspondence (Box 21.)
    - Undated (Folder 1)
    - 1958 (Folder 2)
    - 1959 (Folder 3)
    - 1960 (Folder 4)
    - 1961 (Folder 5)
  - Chronological file of speeches and visits. Holograph notes, typewritten outline and text, correspondence.
    - Department of State speech, May 17, 1957 (Folder 6)
    - Remarks on receiving appt. to Norway, May 23, 1957
    - Opening ceremony of summer session, University of Oslo, July 6, 1957
    - American Women's Club of Oslo, September 10, 1957
    - Norwegian Defense College, December 12, 1957
    - "Some Basic Concepts of American Foreign Policy in the Mid-Twentieth Century," Bergens Handelsforeningen, February 4, 1958 (Folder 7)
    - Roof-raising ceremony, April 25, 1958
    - Minnesota Centennial celebrations, May 5, 1958
    - Remarks onboard ship, Haakon VII, June 30, 1958
    - American Women's Club of Oslo, September 9, 1958
    - "Some Aspects of American Foreign Policy in the Mid-Twentieth Century," Norwegian Defense College, December 12, 1958
    - Remarks on career, December 23, 1958
    - Dedication of Lincoln Statue, Lincoln's Second Inaugural Address, Frogner Park, February 12, 1959 (Folder 8)
    - USAFE Band Concert, May 21, 1959
    - Opening of New Embassy, June 15, 1959
    - American Women's Club of Oslo, September 8, 1959
    - Rustan NIKE Battery Site, October 9, 1959
    - Los Angeles World Affairs Council, December 15, 1959
    - University of Redlands, Redlands, California, December 15, 1959
    - Opening of the PAO Conference, remarks to be read by Charge d'Affaires, Oslo, May 23, 1960 (Folder 9)
    - Commencement Address, American School, Oslo, June 11, 1960
    - World Affairs Center, remarks to community leaders, October 7, 1960
    - Convocation on Peace, Rochester, New York (?), October 14, 1960
    - Remarks, Bangor, Maine, October 21, 1960
    - Trusteeship Council Chamber, remarks to community leaders, United Nations, October 28, 1960
    - "What the U.S. Means to Us," AAUN (American Association for the United Nations?), Englewood, New Jersey, October 30, 1960
    - Foreign Service Women's Association, Washington, D.C., November 9, 1960
    - NGO Briefing, December 7, 1960
    - "Mid-Career Course FSO," U.S. Delegation to U.N., December 9, 1960
    - American Women's Club, Oslo, January 10, 1961 (Folder 10)